Guide to the Leon F. Litwack Collection of Berkeley, California, Protest Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Files, Series I; 4; (4 boxes)
  - File 34 (Box 4, Folder 85-86)
    - AFSCME Local 1695 / 10/14/69 2PP
    - AFT Committee on Arts and Lectures / docketed 08/28/69
    - Alameda County Solidarity Committee / docketed 08/05/69
    - Application form for the Berkeley Faculty Union / nd
    - Berkeley Defense Committee / docketed 04/15/69
    - Berkeley Faculty Union AFT 1474 / docketed 05/26/69
    - Berkeley Tenants Union / docketed 10/20/69
    - Booklet. Center for Educational Change / 04/30/69
    - Call to a demonstration. Berkeley Defense Committee / docketed 10/22/69
    - Call to a demonstration. RSU / docketed 01/15/69 2cc
    - Call to a meeting. Cal Strike Support Committee / docketed 01/20/69
    - Call to a silent vigil. Berkeley Society of Friends / 05/26/69
    - Call to May 4th rally / docketed 04/25/69
    - Call to meeting. SDS / docketed 04/16/69
    - Call to meeting. SDS / docketed 07/31/69 2cc
    - Call to picket Safeway / docketed 10/17/69
    - Call to strike. RSU / docketed 11/20/69
    - Call to teach-in. Berkeley Faculty Union / docketed 05/27/69
    - Campus Friends of the AFT 1570 / docketed 01/20/69
    - Campus International Socialists / docketed 11/20/69
    - Campus Mobilization Committee / docketed 08/13/69
    - Campus PLP docketed 10/07/69
    - Campus Worker-Student Alliance / docketed 11/19/6
    - Campus Worker-Student Alliance / docketed 11/25/69
    - Coalition Against Tuition / docketed 11/25/69
    - Commentary on a report by the Berkeley Faculty Union / Meister 03/11/69 6pp
    - Committee on Liberation or Death (C.O.L.D.) / docketed 10/21/69
    - Communist Party U.S.A. / docketed 10/07/69
    - Concerned Student Employees / docketed 05/27/69
    - English Graduate Association / 05/23/69
    - Essay / Anonymous docketed 07/10/69
    - Instant News Service Vol. 1, No. 9 / 05/26/69
    - Invitation. CCNVA / docketed 01/12/68
    - Iranian Students Association / Azimi 10/17/69
    - Leaflet / Dolphin docketed 10/07/69
    - Leaflet. Huey! Radical Student Union / docketed 04/29/69
    - Leaflet. Abbie Hoffman and the BTU / docketed 12/12/69
    - Leaflet. ASUC referendum / docketed 05/21/69
    - Leaflet. Black anther Party / docketed 06/06/69
    - Leaflet. Call to rally / docketed 05/23/69
    - Leaflet. Campus Young Socialist Alliance / docketed 05/21/69
    - Leaflet. Elect Ray Bietz / docketed 04/15/69
    - Leaflet. Reform or revolution / docketed 07/24/69
    - Leaflet. RSU / docketed 11/24/69
    - Leaflet. SDS / docketed 11/20/69
    - Leaflet. Vote for Holt and Kelly / docketed 04/14/69
    - Leaflet. Vote for Jsus Ruiz / docketed 11/24/69
    - Letter / Lacy 05/22/69
    - Letter / Sealey 01/10/69
    - Letter. Department of Sociology / 05/23/69
    - Letter. The Resistance / docketed 07/18/69
    - Memo / Schwartz and Potter nd
    - Militant Labor Forum / docketed 04/23/69
    - Militant Labor Forum and YSA / docketed 06/06/69
    - New Mobilization Committee / docketed 11/12/69
    - Newspaper. SDS / docketed 09/09/69
    - Notice / Anonymous 05/23/69
    - Office of the Chancellor / Cheit 01/17/69
    - Office of the Dean. College of Letters and Science / Knight 05/28/69 2pp
    - Palo Alto Resistance and Stanford SDS / docketed 11/20/69
    - Pamphlet. Sanitas / docketed 10/02/69
    - Peoples Park Negotiating Committee / docketed 05/26/69
    - Peoples Park Negotiating Committee / docketed 05/27/69
    - Radical Student Union / 08/28/69
    - Radical Student Union / docketed 08/26/69
    - Rally to demand clemency. G.I. Association / docketed 03/14/69
    - Report on campus violence / Heyns 05/23/69 4pp
    - Resolution on Angela Davis/ Office of the Chancellor / 10/03/69
    - Resolution. Academic Senate / Kadish 10/14/69
    - Right On. Newspaper / docketed 10/20/69
    - Selections from the Constitution / docketed 05/25/69
    - SF Mime Troupe / docketed 08/12/69
    - SMC Meeting / docketed 08/12/69
    - Statement. Education Caucus / docketed 04/22/69
    - Statement. Office of the Chancellor / Heyns 04/01/69
    - Statement. Office of the Chancellor / Heyns 07/15/69 4pp
    - Statement. Office of the Chancellor / Johnson 04/04/69 2pp
    - Statement. Officer of the Chancellor / Heyns 05/13/69 2pp
    - Student Mobilization Committee / 11/25/69
    - Student Mobilization Committee / docketed 10/07/69
    - Student Mobilization Committee / docketed 10/22/69
    - Student Mobilization Committee / docketed 10/22/69 2PP
    - Student Union / docketed 04/15/69
    - Students for New Age Unification / docketed 11/20/69
    - The Foundation / docketed 11/20/69
    - The Golden Bear Vol. 1, No. 1 / 04/07/69
    - The Outcry Newspaper / nd
    - The Spartacist / 01/15/69
    - United Front / docketed 10/0769
    - Vote for Scott. Union Party / docketed 04/11/69
    - Wayne Greene Defense Committee / French 10/14/69 3pp
    - World Without War Council / Pickus 10/05/69 2pp
    - Young Peoples Socialist League / docketed 04/22/69
    - Young Peoples Socialist League / docketed 05/27/69
  - File 35 (Box 4, Folder 87-88)
    - Come Together, Right Now. Institute for Ability / docketed 11/18/69
    - Keep Davis. Fire the Regents. Campus International Socialists / 10/02/69
    - On the Arrest of Teaching Assistants. / 02/15/69
    - Strike Now! Campus Friends of the AFT / docketed 02/19/69
    - Strike Now. TWLF / docketed 01/30/69
    - Academic Senate Berkeley Division / St. Lawrence and Chamberlain 05/27/69
    - Academic Senate-Berkeley Division / Powell 05/20/69
    - AFSCME Local 1695 / 02/26/69
    - AFSCME Local 1695 / docketed 01/28/69
    - AFSCME Local 1695 / docketed 02/25/69
    - AFSCME Local 1695 and AFL-CIO / docketed 11/12/69
    - Apartments for rent listing / docketed 10/02/69
    - Arab Students Association / docketed 05/13/69 2cc
    - ASUC / Palmer docketed 06/04/69
    - Berkeley Defense Committee / docketed 10/16/69
    - Berkeley Faculty Union / docketed 05/28/69
    - Booklet. Center for Educational Change / docketed 05/19/69
    - Bumper sticker. Free Speech / nd
    - Call to a meeting. RSU / docketed 02/25/69
    - Call to a rally. AFT-TWLF / docketed 02/14/69
    - Call to a rally. Campus Friends of AFT Local 1570 / docketed 05/15/69
    - Call to a symposium. The Organizing Committee / docketed 03/03/69
    - Call to defend Peoples Park. RSU / docketed 05/29/69
    - Call to defend strikers. RSU / docketed 02/05/69
    - Call to picket against use of DDT / docketed 11/12/69
    - Campus Friends of AFT 1570 / 02/224/69
    - Campus Friends of AFT 1570 / docketed 02/14/69
    - Campus Friends of AFT 1570 / docketed 02/17/69
    - Campus Independent Socialist Club / docketed 02/24/69
    - Campus Womens Liberation / docketed 10/02/69
    - Committee for Self-criticism or Vigilance / docketed 02/05/69
    - El Malcriado. Voice of the Farm Workers / 09/04/69
    - Essay on Asian Studies / docketed 02/19/69 4pp
    - Instant News Service Vol. 1, No. 2 / 05/19/69
    - Invitation. Radical Historians / 12/29/69
    - Leaflet for the Presidio 27 / docketed 02/12/69
    - Leaflet. Come See About Huey. / docketed 04/25/69
    - Leaflet. Off With Their Heads! AFSCME Local 1695 / 03/03/69
    - Leaflet. Wanted for Murder: Standard Oil. / docketed 02/25/69
    - Leaflet. AFT Local 1570 / docketed 02/21/69
    - Leaflet. Bay Area GI-Civilian Anti-war Meeting / docketed 02/24/69
    - Leaflet. Berkeley Defense Committee / docketed 10/16/69
    - Leaflet. RSU / docketed 11/18/69
    - Leaflet. Young Peoples Socialist League / docketed 07/25/69
    - Letter. American Historical Association Council / 10/08/69
    - Letter. United Farm Workers / Velasco 08/01/69
    - Letter. Vietnam Moratorium / docketed 10/01/69 2pp
    - Memo / Schwartz 10/13/69
    - Memo / Waskow and Zinn September 1969 2pp
    - Memo from the university librarian / Skipper 02/14/69
    - Newsletter. Delano Food Caravan / 04/27/68
    - Newsletter. Delano Food Caravan / September 1969
    - November 14 Strike Committee / docketed 11/12/69
    - Office of the Chancellor / Bouwsma 02/19/69
    - Office of the Chancellor / Heyns 02/20/69
    - Office of the Dean. College of Letters and Science / Knight 02/02/69 4pp
    - Office of the Dean. College of Letters and Science / Knight 05/28/69 20pp
    - Oriental Council / docketed 10/02/69
    - Pamphlet. Sanitas / nd
    - Phoenix. Vol. 1, No. 3. Young Americans for Freedom / docketed 05/06/69
    - Program for Action. SDS / docketed 10/02/69
    - Resolution / Office of the Chancellor / Heyns 02/24/69 2pp
    - Resolution. Academic Senate Berkeley Division / 05/23/69
    - Resolutions. A.H.A. / 12/28/69
    - Statement. Office of the Chancellor / Heyns 02/19/69 4pp
    - Statement. Office of the Chancelor / Heyns 05/20/69
    - Strike Support Committee / docketed 02/18/69
    - Student Friends of AFSCME Local 1695 / docketed 02/29/69
    - Student Mobilization Committee / docketed 08/20/69
    - The Smog Project / docketed 05/13/69
    - Third World Liberation Front / docketed 02/21/69
    - Third World Liberation Front. Communique / 02/21/69
    - Third World Liberation Front. Communique #10 / 02/26/69
    - Third World Liberation Front. Communique #12 / 03/03/69
    - Third World Liberation Front. Communique 02/25/69
    - TWLF / 02/26/69
    - TWLF and Strike Support Committee / docketed 01/28/69
    - TWLF and Strike Support Committee. Second printing / docketed 01/30/69
    - UFWOC and AFL-CIO / nd
    - University Bulletin / 09/29/69
    - University Bulletin / 10/06/69
    - Young Peoples Socialist League / docketed 05/19/69
    - Young Peoples Socialist League / docketed 08/28/69
- Newspapers, 1939-2001; Series II; 7; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Newspaper holdings for certain titles, such as Berkeley Barb and The Daily Californian, are extensive, but not comprehensive. Issues may be missing within the date ranges listed in the finding aid.
  - Ally: A Newspaper For Servicemen, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - American Report, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 90-98)
  - Berkeley Barb, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 99-122)
  - Berkeley Barb, 1968-1978 (Box 6, Folder 123-137)
  - Berkeley Daily Gazette, 1964-1965
  - Berkeley Tribe, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - California Newspapers, 1964-2001 (Box 6, Folder 139-146)
  - Campus Report, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 147-148)
  - Capitalism Stinks, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - The Daily Californian, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 150-180)
  - The Daily Californian, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 181-208)
  - The Daily Californian, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 209-232)
  - The Daily Californian, 1970-2001 (Box 10, Folder 233-249)
  - The Daily Cardinal, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - The Daily Gater, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - Employee Press, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - The Every Other Weekly, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - The Faculty Union Reporter, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - French-Algerian War, 1956-1962 (Box 10, Folder 255-260)
    Includes clippings and newspapers pertaining to the Algerian War of Independence (1954-1962).
  - Gadfly: Newsletter Of The Graduate Assembly, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 261)
  - History Graduate Association Newsletter, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 262)
  - The Independent Californian, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 263)
  - The Independent Socialist Supplement, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 264)
  - Journal of Educational Change, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 265)
  - Labor Market Movement, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 266)
  - La Marhe Des Idees, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 267)
  - News Call Bulletin, 1964
  - Oakland Tribune, 1964-1965
  - Peace & Freedom News, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 268)
  - Phoenix, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - The Realist, 1962-1972 (Box 11, Folder 270-278)
  - Réforme, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Right On!, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 280)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1939-1970 (Box 11, Folder 281-287)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also San Francisco Chronicle (from Series II)
  - San Francisco Examiner, 1964
  - San Francisco Sunday Chronicle, 1964
  - Truth Letter, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 288)
  - UC Clerical, Technical, & Professional Employee Press, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 289)
  - University of California - Berkeley, 1964-1968 (Box 11, Folder 290-291)
  - University Of California, Los Angeles: Daily Bruin, 1966 March 9 (Box 11, Folder 292)
  - Various Newspapers, 1964-1984 (Box 11, Folder 293-294)
    See also Various Newspapers (from Series II)
  - The Weekly Golden Bear, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 295)
  - Weekly People, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 296)
- Periodicals, 1959-2004; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Issues may be missing within the date ranges of periodicals listed in the finding aid.
  - The Activist, 1965 January (Box 11, Folder 297)
  - Bancroft Library Presents Taking Park: Free Speech Movement And The Legacy Of Social Protest, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 298)
  - The Berkeley Revolt, 1965 January (Box 11, Folder 299)
  - California Legislature: Senate Daily Journal, circa 1969 (Box 11, Folder 300)
  - California Monthly, 1965-2004 (Box 11, Folder 301)
  - Commemorator: Publication And Distribution Sessions, undated (Box 11, Folder 302)
  - Frontier, 1965 April (Box 11, Folder 303)
  - Free Speech Movement's Sounds And Songs Of The Demonstration!, undated (Box 11, Folder 304)
  - Graduate Student Journal, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 305)
  - Intergroup Relations Newsletter, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 306)
  - NAACP Legal Defense And Education Fund: Jobs For Blacks, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 307)
  - National Alliance Against Racist And Political Repression: A People's Salute To The Alliance, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 308)
  - Newsletter Of The Council For Civic Unity Of San Francisco, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 309)
  - Photocopies (Box 11, Folder 310)
  - Radical America, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 311)
  - Radical Student Union: Vietnam: The Fight For Freedom, circa 1969 (Box 11, Folder 312)
  - Richard: Portrait Of A Vietnam War Register, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 313)
  - Saturday Review, 1965 January (Box 11, Folder 314)
  - Second Thoughts On Berkeley, by Sidney Hook, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 315)
  - SLATE, 1967-1971 (Box 11, Folder 316-317)
  - SLATE (About SLATE), 1959 (Box 11, Folder 318)
  - Spider, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - Steps: Journal Of The Free University Of Berkeley, 1966 December (Box 12, Folder 320)
  - Union Report, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 321)
  - University Of California Academic Senate, 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 322-324)
  - The Writings Of Joachim Joesten, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 325)
  - Young Socialist, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 326)
- Sound Recordings, 1964-1969; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Phonograph records, 1964-1969 (Box 13 (Record album storage), Folder 327)
    Includes two 12-inch (30-cm) 33 1/3 rpm phonographic records: Free Speech Movement's sounds & songs of the demonstration (Berkeley, CA: Free Speech Movement-Records, 1964) and What Shall They Read? (Berkeley, CA: Pacifica Archive Record Foundation, 1968); and two 7-inch 45 rpm phonographic records: Joy to UC: free speech carols (San Francisco: Cireco Music, 1964) and Where have you been today, James Rector? by Kandeda Montgomery (Richmond, CA: LL Liblor Records, 1969).
- Oversize, 1964-1965; 0.38; (2 boxes)
  - File 17 (from Series I) (Box 14, Folder 328)
  - Berkeley Daily Gazette (from Series II), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 329-332)
  - News Call Bulletin (from Series II), 1964 (Box 15, Folder 333)
  - Oakland Tribune (from Series II), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - San Francisco Chronicle (from Series II), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 335-337)
  - San Francisco Examiner (from Series II), 1964 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - San Francisco Sunday Chronicle (from Series II), 1964 (Box 15, Folder 339)
  - Various Newspapers (from Series II), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 340-341)